Career Objective:

To seek a position as MS SQL DBA/Technical support/Product Support in the field of IT – Infrastructure Management Services to execute my 6 + years of experience. My strength is business awareness, which enables me to permanently streamline infrastructure and applications with full dedication. Ability to learn and work in new challenging projects.

Work Experience:

Associate Support Engineer Aperta Ltd, Coimbatore April 2016 - Present

Application Support:

- 2.10 years provide Facility Management Support for Cheque Truncation System at Syndicate, CBI and UCO bank service branch data center across India.
- Providing the technical support to CBI, UCO Bank and Syndicate Bank Internal and External End Users across India regarding technical issues in CTS.
- Travel across India for the product installation and training.
- Responsible for configuration and maintenance of Data center and DR setup.
- Customize the Aperta desktop application in CTS as per the new project requirement.

Database Support:

- 2.5 Years experience in MS SQL Server management in CTS datacenter at Banking Sector.
- Working and diagnose the problems in SQL 2005,2008 express and SQL Server 2012,2014 Server installation, configuration of standalone and cluster environments.
- Worked in upgradation and Migration of SQL Server from older versions.
- Knowledge in SQL Server user management.
- Knowledge in applying Service packs, Security patches and Hot fixes.
- Knowledge in Mirroring, Replication and Always on Available Groups for DR and HA requirements.
- Monitoring the SQL Server using SQL Server Monitoring Tools.
- Create query, views, cursor, Import and Export data in MS SQL server as per the requirements.
- Refine and automate regular processes, track issues, and document changes.
- Responsible for Scheduled Daily and weekly data backups and restoration into standby setup.
- Basic knowledge to create and manage BAT files to automate the repeated process.

Associate Customer Engineer HCL Services Ltd, Dehradun Nov 2012 - April 2016

- 3.5 years' experience in Union Bank of India and Oriental Bank of Commerce regional office at Dehradun as a Facility Management support for desktops and banking applications.
- Handled IT Asset management for both the banks.
- Maintained the Symantec Antivirus server.
- Provided remote support for both the bank's branches at Dehradun regional office.
- Managed mailing system, Windows Trouble shooting, Hardware trouble shooting and PC Assembling.

Education:

Course	Institute	Duration	Marks
Dip - ECE	Nachimuthu Polytechnic College	2009 - 2012	87%
SSLC	JRC Higher Sec School	2008 - 2009	93%

Certificate:

MCP: MS SQL 2012/2014 (Administering SQL Server Databases)

Additional Experience:

- Paper presentations on different topics in state and national levels at college time.
- Worked at SUNFLASH INFOTECH Hardware and networking company as a part timer in college time.

Softwares:

- **Desktop** Windows XP,7,8,8.1 and 10
- Server Windows 2003,2008,2012 and 2012 R2
- Database SQL 2005,2008,2017 express editions and SQL Server 2012,2014
- Virtual Machine Hyper -V, VMware Workstation

Languages:

- Tamil Read, write and Speak
- English Read, write and Speak
- Hindi Speak

Skills:

- Vendor Management
- Project Documentation
- Communication Skills
- IT Asset Management

Personal Information:

Address

Boduvarpatty (PO), Oddanchatram (TK), Dindigul (Dist), Tamilnadu 624614

Phone

+91-9585573158

E-Mail

kumar09ec38@gmail.com

Declaration:

I hereby declare that all the details furnished above are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.